<!-- 
  IzSound manual
  
  Copyright (c) 2003, 2004 Julien PONGE. All Rights Reserved.
  
  http://www.izforge.com/
  <julien@izforge.com>
  <julien_ponge@yahoo.fr>

  :xml.root=manual.xml:
 -->

<chapter id="dsp">
<title>The DSP units</title>

<sect1>

  <title>Overview</title>
  
  <figure>
    <title>A DSP unit</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject><imagedata fileref="dsp.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  
  <para>The way that the DSP units work is very simple. The sound stream is made of samples,
  represented by floating-point values in the [-1.0, 1.0] range. Each unit has some input and
  output slots. A slot is made to transmit the data from/to a DSP unit. The number of these slots
  depend of the DSP unit. These numbers are fixed and are 0-based.</para>
  
  <para>A DSP unit can be connected to other ones by connecting one of its output slot to one
  input slot of another DSP unit. The whole process is actually very simple. Once the connections
  are established, you can use the DSP construction that you have made.</para>
  
  <figure>
    <title>A typical DSP chaining</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject><imagedata fileref="sample-chain.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</sect1>

<sect1>

  <title>Making it work</title>
  
  <para>Once you have connected your DSP units, you certainly want to make it run. The way it works
  in IzSound is pretty simple. All you have to do is to invoke the <methodname>run()</methodname>
  method of all of your source DSP units. By "source DSP units", you must understand "the units
  that have no input".</para>
  
  <para>Once you have invoked the <methodname>run()</methodname> method of all the source DSP
  units, the sound stream will be propaged to the subsequent ones and so on until the final units.
  Most of the time, the final units play or record the sound.</para>
  
  <para>To produce a continuous sound flow, you simply have to iterate on calling the
  <methodname>run()</methodname> methods. Working with IzSound is that simple.</para>

</sect1>

<sect1>

  <title>Implementing your DSP units</title>
  
  <para>Implementing your DSP units is quite simple. Indeed, you just have to concentrate on the
  actual sound data processing work. All the chaining logic is embedded in the
  <classname>DspUnit</classname> class. Every unit inherits from <classname>DspUnit</classname>.
  </para>
  
  <para>The <methodname>run()</methodname> method of <classname>DspUnit</classname> invokes a
  virtual protected method named <methodname>performDsp()</methodname>. This method is of type
  <type>void</type> and takes no parameter. This is where you have to perform your job.</para>
  
  <para>The data that you can get from the input slots is available from the
  <varname>m_inputSlots</varname> attribute. It is a vector of pointers to
  <classname>SlotData</classname> instances. A <classname>SlotData</classname> is actually an
  instance of a <classname>deque&lt;double&gt;</classname> template. You should refer top the API
  for more informations.</para>
  
  <para>On the same way, the output slots are available through the <varname>m_outputSlots</varname>
  attribute, which is in fact the input slot of the next DSP unit it is connected to. Everytime the
  <methodname>performDsp()</methodname> method is invoked, you have 'fresh' data in the input slots.
  A DSP unit is expected to manually clear the output slots data before putting the processed data
  in.</para>
  
</sect1>

</chapter>