<!-- 
  IzSound manual
  
  Copyright (c) 2003, 2004 Julien PONGE. All Rights Reserved.
  
  http://www.izforge.com/
  <julien@izforge.com>
  <julien_ponge@yahoo.fr>

  :xml.root=manual.xml:
 -->

<chapter id="intro">
<title>Introduction</title>

<sect1>

  <title>IzSound overview</title>
  
  <para>IzSound is a stream-oriented sound processing library. It has been designed
  around small DSP units that can be chained together to operate on the sound data
  stream. While there are already several libraries of this kind, most of them are
  either too simplists or too complicated. What's more, they are often written in
  the C programming language and lead to libraries having a lot of functions and
  data structures. Using an object oriented language can dramatically ease the
  learning process by having a clearer overview.</para>
  
  <para>That's why IzSound is written in C++ in order to use the object oriented
  paradigms. Moreover, the C++ STL brings the concepts of generic programming and
  IzSound makes an intensive use of both the containers and the algorithms brought
  by the STL. This way it is built on both well tested data containers and
  algorithmic bricks.</para>
  
  <para>IzSound in itself is a very small library containing the <classname>DspUnit</classname>
  class. It embeds the chaining and streaming logic of the DSP units. There is another library
  named stdizdsp which contains a set of DSP units covering various domains (OGG files reading,
  crossfading, pitching and so on).</para>
  
</sect1>

<sect1>

  <title>Internet resources</title>
  
  <para>The official IzSound homepage is located at
  <ulink url="http://www.izforge.com/izsound/">http://www.izforge.com/izsound/</ulink>.
  Some developper services are provided by BerliOS:
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>bugs tracking</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>patchs management</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>tasks management</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>CVS repository</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>files releases</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>anonymous FTP space</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <para>The source code releases are available from BerliOS as <filename>.tar.bz2</filename>
  files. It is always distributed along with an MD5 checksum as well as a GnuPG signature.</para>

</sect1>

<sect1>

  <title>Licensing</title>
  
  <para>IzSound is distributed under a 3 clauses BSD-style license. Here are the exact terms of
  the license agreement:
  <screen>&izsound-license;</screen>
  </para>
  
  <para>You must be aware that although IzSound is released under a BSD-style license, some DSP
  units might require a library which is released under a license which has more constraints.
  It may also use third-party code published on a more restrictive license.
  Those DSP units can be disabled by the <filename>configure</filename> script before you build
  IzSound. The following table sums-up the licensing constraints put on the applications that use
  IzSound.
  <table>
    <title>Licensing constraints, depending on the DSP that are built in IzSound</title>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <thead>
        <row>
          <entry><para>DSP unit</para></entry>
          <entry><para>Licensing constraints</para></entry>
        </row>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <row>
          <entry><para><classname>LibaoOutput</classname></para></entry>
          <entry><para>Your application license has to be compatible with the GNU GPL.
          The DSP unit source code is licensed under the terms of the IzSound license.
          </para></entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry><para><classname>MadDecoder</classname></para></entry>
          <entry><para>Your application license has to be compatible with the GNU GPL.
          The DSP unit source code is licensed under the terms of the GNU GPL.</para></entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry><para>Other units</para></entry>
          <entry><para>IzSound license</para></entry>
        </row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </table>
  </para>

</sect1>

</chapter>
