<!--

  IzSound manual
  
  Copyright (c) 2003, 2004 Julien PONGE. All Rights Reserved.
  
  http://www.izforge.com/
  <julien@izforge.com>
  <julien_ponge@yahoo.fr>

  :xml.root=manual.xml:
  
-->

<appendix id="thirdparty">

  <title>Third-party code</title>
  
  <para>IzSound makes use of some third-party code. A big 'thank you' to their respective authors.
  Here is the list of these third-party codes as well as their copyright notices.</para>
  
  <itemizedlist>
  
    <listitem><para>The <classname>MadDecoder</classname> class is based on the
    <filename>madlld.c</filename> program from Bertrand Petit.</para>
    <screen><![CDATA[
/****************************************************************************
 * madlld.c -- A simple program decoding an mpeg audio stream to 16-bit     *
 * PCM from stdin to stdout. This program is just a simple sample           *
 * demonstrating how the low-level libmad API can be used.                  *
 *--------------------------------------------------------------------------*
 * (c) 2001, 2002 Bertrand Petit                                            *
 *                                                                          *
 * Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without       *
 * modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions       *
 * are met:                                                                 *
 *                                                                          *
 * 1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright        *
 *    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.         *
 *                                                                          *
 * 2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above               *
 *    copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following           *
 *    disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided       *
 *    with the distribution.                                                *
 *                                                                          *
 * 3. Neither the name of the author nor the names of its contributors      *
 *    may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this          *
 *    software without specific prior written permission.                   *
 *                                                                          *
 * THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE AUTHOR AND CONTRIBUTORS ``AS IS''       *
 * AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED        *
 * TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A          *
 * PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR OR       *
 * CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL,             *
 * SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT         *
 * LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF         *
 * USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND      *
 * ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,       *
 * OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT       *
 * OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF       *
 * SUCH DAMAGE.                                                             *
 *                                                                          *
 ****************************************************************************/

]]></screen>
    </listitem>
    
    <listitem><para>The <classname>MadDecoder</classname> class makes use of
    third party code licensed under the terms of the GNU GPL. As a consequence,
    this class is licensed under the terms of the GNU GPL.
    The GNU GPL terms are provided in the IzSound sources distribution in the
    <filename>COPYING.GPL</filename> file.</para>
    <screen><![CDATA[
/*
 * This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify
 * it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
 * the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or
 * (at your option) any later version.
 *
 * This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
 * but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
 * MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
 * GNU General Public License for more details.
 *
 * You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
 * along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
 * Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA
 */

]]></screen>
    </listitem>
  
  </itemizedlist>
  
</appendix>
